{
    "id": "bd4a3555aa3843bdac984ddccfbeb971",
    "title": "Subject Verb Agreement",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Time and tide ………………………. for none.",
            "description": "If two nouns together represent one idea or refer to one person or thing, the verb is singular.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "waits"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ec80fb5a4e67467e9e49a65343928b37"
        },
        {
            "question": "The state of his affairs ………………………… sure to cause anxiety to his creditors.",
            "description": "Here the real subject is the singular expression ‘state’.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bc5dbad304ff45d49edac821a0eddf9f"
        },
        {
            "question": "My father and I ………………………… soccer.",
            "description": "When two singular subjects are connected by ‘and’, the verb is plural.",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "likes"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d8aaefba2f8e4339ae98d54d03df9e58"
        },
        {
            "question": "He or his friend …………………………… the secret.",
            "description": "When two singular subjects are connected by or, the verb is singular.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knows"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9a18c98e54684c2a922727ecb8b87816"
        },
        {
            "question": "He or his friends ………………………… responsible for this.",
            "description": "When a singular noun and a plural noun are connected by ‘or’, the verb agrees with the number of the noun closest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "46a63aab69334d6fb96abe7204db7825"
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither my friends nor I …………………………….. interested in this offer.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with neither and nor, the verb agrees with the number and person of the noun nearest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "are",
                "is"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "13a659dc34b047e0ae06901905392f60"
        },
        {
            "question": "Either he or you …………………………. mistaken.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with either and or, the verb agrees with the number and person of the noun nearest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "am",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3dc14450c13c4ac3b29a219c83cb6bb4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Oil as well as gas ………………………… imported to India.",
            "description": "When we connect two subjects with as well as, the verb usually agrees with the first subject in number and person.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5091eed0fa3245fb8f55b99766b84508"
        },
        {
            "question": "The mother along with her children ………………………… waiting in the lobby.",
            "description": "When we connect two subjects with ‘along with’, the verb agrees with the first subject in number and person.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1b43f15a584e4df7bedf079c67637a50"
        },
        {
            "question": "Many a man …………………………. lost his life at sea.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after the expression ‘many a man’.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "64710cbc0bb34a3395f8a25330e4f69b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Pickwick Papers ……………………….. written by Charles Dickens.",
            "description": "The names of books and magazines are all singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "98fa1f1938db4662a6cb83ee4f6c62b4"
        },
        {
            "question": "None of my shirts ………………………… clean.",
            "description": "None can be followed by a singular or plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "050445657ee646d8b23c86a289725dcc"
        }
    ]
}